伊森 愿意娶朱莉娅 为你的合法妻子吗	Do you, Ethan, take Julia to be your lawful wedded wife?
我愿意	I do.
不离不弃 爱她 珍惜她 尊重她并保护她	To have, to hold, to love, cherish, honor, and protect?
保护她免遭已知和未知的恐惧	To shield from terrors known and unknown?
-对她说谎 欺骗她 -什么	-To lie, to deceive... -What?
过双重生活 无法阻止她被人绑架	To live a double life, to fail to prevent her abduction,
抹去她的身份 逼迫她销声匿迹	erase her identity, force her into hiding,
夺走她所知的一切	take away all she has known...
别说了	Stop.
企图自私 徒劳且快速地	...in a selfish, futile, fleeting attempt...
逃避真实的自我	...to escape your own true self?
拜托 别说了	Please, stop.
朱莉娅 你愿意选择接受吗	And, Julia, do you choose to accept?
不要	Don't.
-我愿意 -不要	-I do. -No.
你应该杀了我的 伊森	You should have killed me, Ethan.
（贝尔法斯特）
命运对勇士低语	Fate whispers to the warrior...
风暴即将来临	A storm is coming.
勇士低声回应	And the warrior whispers back...
我就是风暴	I am the storm.
（荷马史诗《奥德赛》）
（身份确认 伊森·马修亨特）
晚上好 亨特先生	Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
无政府主义者所罗门连恩	The anarchist Solomon Lane.
自从你两年前抓到他	Since you captured him 2 years ago,
他从世界舞台消失 却产生了令人意想不到的后果	his absence from the world stage has had unintended consequences.
他所创建的辛迪加由叛变的 秘密特工组成 继续在全球肆虐	His Syndicate of rogue covert operatives continues to wreak havoc around the globe.
中情局的特别行动科	The CIA's Special Activities Division
一直在不屈不挠地追捕连恩的 敌对分子精英网络	has relentlessly hunted Lane's elite network of hostiles.
但很多人依然不为人知 逍遥法外	But many remain unknown and at large.
这个极端主义分化团体的残余分子	The remnants of this extremist splinter cell
自称为使徒	refer to themselves as "The Apostles."
从那时起 他们一直采用雇佣恐怖分子政策	They have since adopted a policy of terror-for-hire,
让他们更具威胁性	making them an even greater threat.
他们引发了最近爆发的天花疫情	They are responsible for the recent smallpox outbreak
疫情范围包括印控克什米尔	in Indian-controlled Kashmir,
和中巴边境	along the borders of China and Pakistan,
威胁全球三分之一的人口	threatening one-third of the world's population.
这种流行病的传播目前受到控制	The epidemic is being contained,
但情报表明	but intelligence would indicate
一名新客户雇佣了使徒 准备进行一项更具野心的行动	that a new client has hired the Apostles for a more ambitious operation.
此人联络了他们	They have been contacted by this man,
一名身份不明的极端主义分子 我们只知道其化名约翰·拉克	an unidentified extremist  known only by the code name John Lark,
他写下了这份毁灭性的宣言	author of this apocalyptic manifesto
呼吁摧毁当前的世界秩序	calling for the destruction of the current world order.
（不经受巨大苦难 绝不会有和平）
据信挪威核武器专家 尼尔斯德尔布鲁克的失踪	It is believed Lark is responsible for the disappearance
就是拉克所为	of Norwegian nuclear weapons specialist Nils Delbruuk.
德尔布鲁克博士 强烈表达了反宗教观点	Dr. Delbruuk's security  clearance was revoked
此后 他的安全权限被取消了	after he expressed fiercely anti-religious views.
与此同时 使徒一直	Meanwhile, the Apostles  have been in contact
与东欧地下组织成员联络	with elements of  the Eastern European underworld,
他们有三枚钚弹	who are in possession of three plutonium cores
这些钚弹是从俄罗斯东部的 导弹基地偷来的	stolen from a missile base in eastern Russia.
这表明约翰拉克和使徒	This would indicate that John Lark and the Apostles
狼狈为奸 以获得能发挥威力的核武器	are working together to acquire functioning nuclear weapons.
核应急支援分队估计 拥有德尔布鲁克学识的人	NEST estimates that a man with Delbruuk's knowledge,
使用相应原料	using the materials in play,
能在短短72小时内建造三件核武器	could complete three nuclear weapons in as little as 72 hours.
这些设备便于携带	These devices would be man-portable
能在一夜之间部署到地球上任何地方	and deployable anywhere on Earth overnight.
约翰拉克和使徒持有	In the hands of John Lark and the Apostles,
这些武器 将对数百万人	these weapons represent an unprecedented threat
造成史无前例的威胁	to countless millions.
你的任务 如果你选择接受	Your mission,  should you choose to accept it,
就是不惜采取任何手段	is to prevent the Apostles from acquiring plutonium
阻止使徒获得钚弹	using any means at your disposal.
如果你和不可能任务小组的成员 被抓或遇害	If you or any members of your IMF team  are caught or killed,
秘书长会对你们的行动予以否认	the Secretary will disavow any knowledge of your actions.
祝你好运 伊森	Good luck, Ethan.
这段信息将在五秒后自行销毁	This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
（柏林）
他来晚了	He's late.
-他从来不会晚到 -他会来的	-He's never late. -He'll be here.
我有不祥的预感	I don't like it.
这家伙很可疑 让我觉得很不安	Something about this guy just really gives me the creeps.
好吧 放松点	Okay, just relax.
我很放松	I'm relaxed.
你听起来一点都不放松	You don't sound relaxed.
卢瑟 他听起来很放松吗	Luther, does he sound relaxed to you?
他听起来很害怕	He sounds terrified.
拜托 我不害怕 我只是有不祥的预感	Please, I'm not terrified. I just have a bad feeling is all.
我还以为你说你很放松	I thought you said you were relaxed.
同时感到放松和极度不安完全有可能	It's entirely possible to be relaxed and extremely uneasy at the same time.
-才不会 -你向来如此	-No, it's not. -You do it all the time.
-我才没有 -你就是	-No, I don't. -Yes, you do.
他才不是	No, he doesn't.
我应该相信你完全放松	I'm supposed to believe that you are perfectly relaxed,
-此时此刻 -班吉	-right here, now... -Benji.
在漆黑的通道里 等着 从一个精神变态者那里购买黑市钚弹	...in a dark alleyway, waiting to buy black-market plutonium from a psychopath.
班吉 我不会让你出事的	Benji, I won't let anything happen to you.
-好吧 -你瞧 班吉	-Okay. -See, Benji,
你很安全	you're perfectly safe.
你说得轻巧 你在面包车里	That's easy for you to say, you're in the van.
你想做外勤工作 硬汉	Well, you wanted to be in the field, tough guy.
卢瑟 我今晚想待在面包车里	And tonight, Luther, I would like to be in the van!
他来了	He's here.
老天	Oh, God.
把钱准备好 卢瑟	Have that money ready, Luther.
收到	Copy.
伊森 你收到了吗	Ethan, do you copy?
你收到了吗	Do you copy?
我们到底要不要交易	Are we finally gonna do this or not?
我在这一行得以生存 全凭脑子里的一个声音	I have survived in this business with the help of a voice in my head.
这个声音从来都不会出错 无论我何时跟你见面	This voice is never wrong. And whenever I meet you,
它都会告诉我同一件事	it tells me the same thing.
什么	What's that?
没什么	Nothing.
我是来做生意的 叫那个声音做决定吧	I'm here to do business. Tell the voice to flip a coin.
那是怎么回事	What's that?
这是铍棒 会导致	This is a beryllium rod, which is causing
钚弹里的钚产生反应	a reaction with the plutonium inside the core.
货真价实	That's them.
钱呢	The money?
钱	The money.
把钱拿来	Bring the money.
卢瑟 把钱拿来	Luther, bring the money.
我们需要那笔钱 卢瑟	We're gonna need that money, Luther.
干掉他们	Kill them.
我来拿 	I got it!
卢瑟 收到了吗	Luther, do you copy?
卢瑟 	Luther!
卢瑟 请回答	Luther, come in.
卢瑟现在不在	Luther's not here right now.
使徒能为你做什么事 亨特	What can the Apostles do for you, Hunt?
-你想怎样 -你被包围了 亨特	-What do you want? -You're boxed in, Hunt.
把钚弹给我们 然后离开	Give us the plutonium and walk away.
班吉 把车开过来	Benji, get the car.
-我办不到 -班吉	-I don't think I can do that. -Benji.
把车开过来	Get the car.
我们做一笔交易吧 亨特	We'll make you a deal, Hunt.
把钚弹给我们 我们就不会杀死你的朋友	Give us the plutonium and we won't kill your friend.
不要 伊森 不要为了我这么做 	Don't you do it, Ethan! Not for me!
我会数到三	I'm gonna count to three.
一	One.
-二 -卢瑟	-Two. -Luther...
-抱歉 -三	-...I'm sorry. -Three.
抱歉 我没有别的办法	I'm sorry. I didn't know what else to do.
我们没事了	We're good.
-你没事吧 -我应该死了	-You okay? -I should be dead.
我们都应该死了	We should all be dead.
我们为何没死	Why aren't we?
钚弹在哪	Where's the plutonium?
不见了	It's gone.
如果你刚收看新闻	If you're just joining us,
三次大爆炸同时发生	three massive explosions have gone off simultaneously
看起来像是一次协同攻击	in what appears to be a coordinated attack.
这是从罗马俯瞰梵蒂冈的现场图像	This image is live in Rome, looking toward the Vatican
我们的摄像机 最近只能拍摄到这个距离	and is as close as our cameras can get.
据信爆炸发生当时	It is believed that the Pope was in residence
教皇正在自己的住宅中	at the time of the blast.
以下也是现场播报 我们从城郊俯瞰耶路撒冷	Also live, we're looking at Jerusalem from just outside the city.
以下也是现场播报 麦加圣城	Also live, the holy city of Mecca
来自位于红海的罗纳德里根号 航空母舰 就在沙特阿拉伯海岸线上	from the USS Ronald Reagan in the Red Sea off the coast of Saudi Arabia.
已探测到辐射	Radiation has been detected,
表明核武器被用于	indicating that nuclear weapons were used
这些惨绝人寰的攻击中	in these unspeakable attacks.
-伊森 是时候了 -暂时不知道伤亡情况 但我们认为	-Ethan, it's time. -No word on casualties yet,  but we can assume
死亡人数会大得惊人	the death toll is catastrophic.
早前的报道表明使用的武器	Early reports suggest the weapons used
需要高度专业化知识	would require highly specialized knowledge
极少有人拥有这种知识	that very few people possess.
现在的问题是 谁会攻击 这三个圣地原因是什么	The question now is who would attack all three of these holy sites? And why?
攻击恰好发生在同一时刻	The attacks occurred  at precisely the same moment,
大约一小时前	just over an hour ago,
东部时间凌晨四点	at 4:00 a.m. Eastern Time.
攻击发生后 不出几分钟	Within minutes of the attack,
国会下令紧急休会	Congress ordered an emergency recess
国会大厦的人员全部撤离	and the Capitol Building was evacuated.
总统乘坐空军一号离开华府	The President left Washington on Air Force One.
白宫宣布进入紧急状态	The White House has declared a state of emergency,
让部队处于高度警戒状态	placing the military on highest alert.
请让我们单独谈谈	Would you excuse us, please?
德尔布鲁克博士	Dr. Delbruuk.
我们知道你是谁	We know who you are.
我们读了宣言 找到了你的实验室	We read the manifesto, we found your lab.
不经受巨大苦难	There has never been peace
绝不会有和平	without first a great suffering.
苦难越深重 和平就越伟大	The greater the suffering, the greater the peace.
瞧 这会让他们团结一致	See, this will unite them.
他们读完这份宣言后 就会明白	When they read this manifesto, they'll all understand.
永远不会有人读那份宣言	Nobody's gonna read that manifesto, ever.
我能向你保证	I can promise you that.
今天是几号	What day is it?
我在这里多久了	How long have I been here?
你记得的最后一件事是什么	What's the last thing you remember?
我在开车	I was driving.
有人撞到我	Someone hit me.
那是两周前的事了	That was two weeks ago.
-两周 -两周	-Two weeks? -Two weeks.
这是你的手机 对吗	This is yours, isn't it?
拉克通过它跟你联络	It's how Lark communicated with you.
-拉克 -约翰拉克	-Lark? -John Lark.
-我们对他无所不知 -你们一无所知	-We know all about him. -You know nothing.
这部手机上的信息 可以帮助我们找到他	There's information in this phone that could lead us to him.
你有密码	And you have the passcode.
你们认为拉克是敌人	You think Lark is the enemy?
不过你们	But you,
无论你们是谁 你们才是敌人	well, whoever you are, you are the enemy.
你们让体制得以存活	You're why the system survives.
-苦难持续不断 -闭嘴 	-Why the suffering goes on. -Shut up!
我们不在乎你 我们想要拉克	We don't care about you. We want Lark.
我们做笔交易怎么样	What if we make a deal?
不 不能做交易 卢瑟	No, there's no deal, Luther.
出去	Step outside.
让我跟他单独待五分钟	Give me five minutes with this guy.
伊森 我不能让你这么做 我们不是这样的人	Ethan, I can't let you do that. That's not who we are.
我们或许需要重新考虑这点	Then maybe we need to reconsider that.
如果他们在电视上把宣言读出来呢	What if they read the manifesto on the air?
什么你们能这么做	What? You can do that?
我们打一通电话就能办到	We can do it with a phone call.
如果他读出拉克的宣言	Well, if he reads Lark's manifesto...
不行	No.
我会告诉你们密码	I'll give you the passcode.
伊森 	Ethan! Ethan!
想一想 伊森	Think, Ethan.
请为大局着想	Think of the greater good, please.
对 你该这么做	Yeah, you do that.
长官	Sir.
不 他不肯合作	No, he won't cooperate.
是的 长官 如果我们在电视上	Yes, sir. If we read the manifesto
读出宣言	on the air.
我很抱歉 长官	I'm sorry, sir.
贸易和全球市场猛跌	Trading and global markets plummeted.
请稍后 我获悉我们会收到其他信息	Stand by. I'm told we're about to get some additional information.
我刚收到来自一份 来自尼尔斯德尔布鲁克的文件	I've just been handed a document from Nils Delbruuk,
他是一位核武器专家	a nuclear weapons specialist
他宣称自己建造了 这些攻击中使用的武器	who claims to have built the weapons used in these attacks.
我受命要将这份宣言完整地读出来	I've been asked to read  this manifesto in its entirety.
（恐怖分子发表声明）
不经受巨大苦难	There has never been peace
绝不会有和平	without first a great suffering.
苦难越深重 和平就越伟大	The greater the suffering, the greater the peace.
人类走向自我灭亡	As mankind is drawn to his self-destruction
就像飞蛾扑火	like a moth to the candle,
所谓的和平捍卫者	the so-called defenders of peace,
教堂 政府 执法机构	the church, the government, the law,
孜孜不倦地工作 以拯救人类毁灭自己	work tirelessly to save humanity from itself.
现在帮不到你们了	It's not gonna help you now.
但为了避免这场灾难	But by averting disaster,
他们的行动延迟了和平的到来	they serve to delay a peace…
木已成舟	What's done is done.
和平只能来自 不可避免的烈火洗礼	...that can only come through an inevitable baptism of fire.
我带给你们的苦难不是末日的开始	The suffering I bring you is not the beginning of the end.
而是更好的	It is the beginning
相互理解的开始	of a greater mutual understanding…
拿到手了吗	Did we get it?
这是迈向	It is the first step
终极人类兄弟情谊的第一步	toward the ultimate brotherhood of man.
拿到手了	We got it.
我带给你们的苦难	The suffering I bring you
是终极和平的桥梁	is the bridge to ultimate peace.
行动	Go.
拿到手了吗	Did we get it?
当然拿到手了	Of course we got it.
我告诉过你 我们会拿到手的	I told you we'd get it.
我不明白	I don't understand.
攻击没发生	The attacks didn't happen?
你遭遇的车祸发生在一小时前	The car accident you were in, that was an hour ago.
当时开另一辆车的人是我	I was driving the other car.
木已成舟	What's done is done,
我们说了算	when we say it's done.
碟中谍6：全面瓦解
（德国拉姆施泰因空军基地）
长官	Sir.
你解锁的手机让我们找到了 一个位于冰岛的服务器	That phone you unlocked led us to a server in Iceland
我们设法解密了 约翰拉克和这个女人之间的	where we managed to decrypt a communiqué
一次谈话	between John Lark and this woman:
阿拉娜米萨珀拉斯 她是一位活跃分子和慈善家	Alana Mitsopolis, activist and philanthropist,
她所做的慈善工作	whose charity work
为她赢得了 白寡妇 这一绰号	has earned her the nickname the White Widow.
这是她从事真正生意的幌子 军火贸易 洗钱	It's all a front for her real trade: arms dealing, money laundering.
广泛的政治人脉为她提供了保护	Extensive political connections provide her with protection.
拉克和白寡妇今晚会碰面	Lark and the Widow are meeting tonight
商讨一个不明包裹的递送事宜	to negotiate delivery of an unspecified package,
我们只能认为这就是我们丢失的钚弹	which we can only assume is our missing plutonium.
他们会在巴黎大皇宫的 一个私人会所见面	They'll make contact in a private lounge at the Grand Palais in Paris
她届时会举行她的年度集资募捐活动	during her annual fundraising event.
档案里面有相关详情	The details are in the file.
如果拉克到午夜时分还不出现	If Lark isn't there by midnight,
白寡妇会离开	the Widow will leave
把包裹卖给出价最高的人	and sell the package to the highest bidder.
从现在起 你有两小时的时间 可以找到拉克	Which gives you two hours from now to find Lark.
长官 我需要告诉你一件事	Sir, I think there's something you need to know.
你不用说了	I'm gonna stop you right there.
你在柏林不得不做出艰难选择	You had a terrible choice to make in Berlin:
拿到钚弹还是拯救你的团队成员	Recover the plutonium or save your team.
你选择拯救你的团队成员 现在全世界都处于危险之中	You chose your team, and now the world is at risk.
你内心深处的缺陷	Some flaw deep in your core being
让你无法选择要拯救一条性命 还是数百万条性命	simply won't allow you to choose between one life and millions.
你认为那是软弱的表现	You see that as a sign of weakness.
我认为这是你最大的优势	To me, that's your greatest strength.
这也告诉我 我能信任你 会保护我的性命	It also tells me I can count on you to cover my ass.
因为从中情局转来这里是平级调动 有人说这是降职	Because coming over here from the CIA was a lateral move, some say a step down.
但我因为你	But I did it
这么做了	because of you.
别让我后悔	Don't make me regret it.
打电话吧	Make the call.
让飞机熄火	Shut 'em down.
你以为自己在做什么 艾丽卡	What do you think you're doing, Erika?
这或许是你的任务	It may be your mission,
但这是中情局的飞机	but this is the CIA's plane.
没有我的允许 它不能起飞	It doesn't take off without my say-so.
我们没时间玩这一套	We don't have time for this.
我们在巴黎有一队人 拉克一离开大皇宫 他们就会抓住他	I have a team in Paris ready to grab Lark as soon as he leaves the Palais.
一架湾流G550飞机会原地待命 准备把他送往关塔那摩湾海军基地	A G5 standing by to rendition him to Gitmo,
他将在那里接受水刑	where a waterboard is waiting.
我们本来就没时间 花24小时 从一个尚未确认身份的人那里	Spend 24 hours we don't have to pull a confession we can't trust
获取一份不可信的供词不行	from a man we haven't positively identified? No.
我们迫切需要可靠的情报	We need reliable intelligence, and we need it now.
正因为这种情况 不可能任务小组才会存在 	This scenario is precisely why the IMF exists!
不可能任务小组是万圣节闹剧 阿伦	The IMF is Halloween, Alan.
一群戴着橡胶面具的成年人 玩讨糖果游戏	A bunch of grown men in rubber masks playing trick-or-treat.
如果他在柏林没弄丢钚弹	And if he had held on to the plutonium in Berlin,
我们就不会进行此番谈话	we wouldn't be having this conversation.
他的团队成员就会死	And his team would be dead.
是的 他们会死	Yes. They would.
那是他们的本职工作	That's the job.
所以我希望我的手下人参与行动	And that's why I want one of my own men on the scene
对情况作出评估	to appraise the situation.
特别行动科的沃克探员	Agent Walker, Special Activities.
他名声在外	His reputation precedes.
你使用微妙手法	You use a scalpel.
我更喜欢暴力	I prefer a hammer.
不行	The answer is no.
我有直接来自总统的行动指挥权	I have operational authority here, direct from the President.
如果你对此有异议 可以去问他	You have a problem with that, you take it up with him.
我已经问过了 他认同我的观点 我的人去参加任务	I have already, and he agrees with me. My man goes
否则谁都不能去	or no one goes.
不能让任何人从中作梗 妨碍你拿到钚弹	No one comes between you and that plutonium.
亨特 他的团队 或其他其任何人都不行	Not Hunt, not his team, not anyone.
白寡妇在政府的每个层级 都安置了间谍	The White Widow has spies at every level of government.
这架飞机会假充商务班机	This plane is posing as a commercial airliner
这样我们就能从法国领空跳下去 而不被人发现	so we can jump into France undetected.
白寡妇会在午夜时分 跟拉克在贵宾会所见面	The Widow's meeting Lark in the VIP lounge at midnight.
没有事先颁发的电子身份手环 任何人都不能进去	No one will be admitted without a pre-issued electronic I.D. band.
我们获得了拉克手环的	We have acquired the unique RFID number
唯一射频识别码 我们可以通过这些设备	for Lark's band, allowing us to locate it
来确认它的位置	with these.
找到那个身份手环 就会找到拉克	Find that I.D. band, you find Lark.
然后怎么办	Then what?
然后	Then...
我会假扮成他 去跟白寡妇见面	I assume his identity and make contact with the Widow.
她带我们去拿包裹	She takes us to the package.
真的有人会相信这玩意	People actually fall for this shit?
你打算如何让拉克乖乖就范	How do you intend to make Lark cooperate?
我在人群中撞他一下	I bump him in the crowd.
十秒钟后 他就会跟派对上 其他的醉鬼一样	In ten seconds he'll look like any other drunk at the party,
语无伦次 百依百顺	incoherent and completely pliable.
我借用他的脸之后	After I borrow his face,
你带他走出前门 把他交给斯隆的撤离小队	you walk him out the front door and hand him to Sloane's extraction team.
你没法轻易摆脱我 亨特	You're not getting rid of me that easily, Hunt.
不是这么回事	That's not what this is about.
就是这么回事	Sure it is.
我知道你不想我参加本次特别任务	I know you don't want me on this detail.
但我们面对现实吧	But let's face it:
如果你在柏林做出艰难选择	If you'd made the hard choice in Berlin,
我根本不会在这里	I wouldn't be here.
他们派你去追杀辛迪加探员	And if you hadn't gunned down
如果你没把这些人统统干掉	every Syndicate agent they sent you to find,
我也不会在这里	I wouldn't be here.
没错 我对你无所不知	That's right, I know all about you.
就是因为你 我们才没有活着的 目击证人 可以确认约翰拉克	You're why we don't have a living witness who can identify John Lark
或使徒们的身份	or the Apostles.
如果你对我的办事方法有意见	If you have a problem with my methods,
随时可以选择留下来	you can always stay behind.
你的任务 如果你选择接受	Your mission, should you choose to accept it.
难道不是这样吗	Isn't that the thing?
距离减压还有两分钟	Two minutes to decompression.
穿好装备 白寡妇将于30分钟后跟拉克见面	Suit up. The Widow is meeting Lark in 30 minutes.
距离减压还有十秒钟	Ten seconds to decompression.
你打开氧气瓶了吗	Is your oxygen on?
处于这种海拔高度 没有大气	There is no atmosphere at this altitude.
你最好不要晕死	I don't need you blacking out on me.
嘿 你的平视显示器上 有内置引导系统	Hey, your heads-up display has a built-in guidance system.
要严格遵循	Follow it to the target.
系统通知你以后 才能打开降落伞	Open your chute when the system says,
之前不行 之后更加不行	not before and definitely not after,
否则你脑中闪过的最后一件事	or the last thing that goes through your mind
将是你的膝盖骨 明白吗	will be your kneecaps. Is that clear?
很清楚	Crystal.
我们得谈谈 我们要重新考虑一下	We got to talk. We need to rethink this.
让开 亨特	Out of my way, Hunt.
沃克 我们遇到麻烦了 现在有风暴 我们需要	Walker, we've got a problem. There's a storm. We need to...
别再说话了	Enough talk.
巴黎见	I'll see you in Paris.
快点	Come on, come on, come on.
海拔高度：7620米	Altitude: 25,000 feet.
沃克	Walker?
怎么了 亨特害怕小小的闪电吗	What's the matter, Hunt? You afraid of a little lightning?
海拔高度：6096米	Altitude: 20,000 feet.
混蛋	Son of a bitch.
沃克	Walker?
你收到了吗	Do you copy?
来吧	Come on.
海拔高度：4572米	Altitude: 15,000 feet.
沃克	Walker.
沃克 	Walker!
海拔高度：3048米	Altitude: 10,000 feet.
2743米	9,000.
惨了	Oh, shit.
2438米	8,000.
2134米	7,000.
1829米	6,000.
1524米	5,000.
1219米	4,000.
沃克 	Walker!
914米	3,000.
打开降落伞	Deploy. Deploy. Deploy.
打开降落伞	Deploy. Deploy.
天哪	Oh, God.
你好像没氧气了	Looks like you lost your oxygen.
白寡妇会在那里跟拉克见面	That's where the Widow is meeting Lark.
伊森	Ethan.
-沃克 -伊森 如果你能听见我	-Walker. -Ethan, if you can hear me,
我找到他了	I've got him.
再说一次 在哪里	Say again. Where?
他正朝洗手间走去	He's headed for the bathroom.
-注射器呢 -不需要了	-Where's the needle? -Didn't need it.
把他扶起来	Get him up.
嘿	Hey, hey.
别害羞 人越多越好	Don't be shy, the more the merrier.
别这样 我们又不凶	Come on, we're not mean.
我们可以加入吗 我们又不会咬人的 各位	Can we join you? We won't bite, guys.
可恶	Shit.
-你还能做面具吗 -我需要脸才能做面具	-Can you still make a mask? -I need a face to make a mask.
抱歉 我瞄准的是他的胸部	Sorry. I was aiming for his chest.
-你来这里干什么 -我也很高兴见到你	-What are you doing here? -It's good to see you, too.
抱歉 我有点不明白 你是	I'm sorry, I'm confused. You are...
老朋友	An old friend.
取消撤离行动 目标死亡	Cancel extraction. We're code blue.
派清洁队过来	Send sanitation.
北边的男性洗手间	North men's room.
你没回答我的问题 你来这里干什么	You didn't answer my question. What are you doing here?
这就对了 放轻松 这就对了	That's it. Just take it easy. That's it.
保持头部后仰 直到不出血为止	Just keep your head back until the bleeding stops.
怎么了	What is it?
你们也想要一些吗	You want some, too?
你不是碰巧来这里的 谁派你来的	You're not here by accident. Who sent you?
我不能告诉你	I can't tell you that.
你在干什么	What are you doing?
我跟白寡妇有约	I have a date with the White Widow.
他跟白寡妇有约 你跟他一点都不像	He had a date with the Widow. You look nothing like him.
现在我们得希望他们素未谋面	And now we have to hope they never met.
-希望算不上策略  -你肯定是新来的	-Hope is not a strategy! -Oh, you must be new.
我没得选	I have no other choice.
白寡妇是我们唯一的线索	The White Widow's our only lead.
我得假扮这家伙五分钟时间	I got to be this guy for five minutes.
-别这样做 -什么	-Don't do it. -What?
怎么了你有什么没告诉我	What is it? What aren't you telling me?
你不懂自己卷入了什么	You don't understand what you're involved in.
我不懂自己卷入了什么	I don't understand what I'm involved in.
我不懂自己卷入了什么	I don't understand what I'm involved in?
我卷入了什么	What am I involved in?
如果你要跟白寡妇见面 她三分钟后就离开了	If you're meeting the Widow, she leaves in three minutes.
-伊森  -我会成功的	-Ethan! -I'll make it work.
我叫沃克	The name's Walker.
是吗 不客气	Yeah? You're welcome.
你以为自己在做什么	What do you think you're doing?
-我跟你一起去 -绝对不行	-I'm going with you. -Like hell you are.
有很多人被派来这里杀拉克	People have been sent here to kill Lark.
明摆着嘛	No shit.
不 不是我 合约杀手 受雇的刺客	No, not me. Contractors. Paid assassins.
他们不知道拉克的长相	They don't know what he looks like,
只知道他跟白寡妇在午夜碰面	they only know he's meeting the Widow at midnight.
如果你要把这件事进行到底	If you go through with this,
他们会认为你就是拉克 然后杀了你	they're gonna believe you're Lark and they're gonna kill you.
你怎么知道这一切	How do you know all this?
我不能告诉你	I can't tell you that.
你应该远离谍报工作	You should've stayed out of the game.
你应该跟我一起走	You should've come with me.
本慈善活动 是为了纪念我母亲而发起的	This charity was started in honor of my mother.
认识她的人都了解她的力量	Those of you who knew her understood her strength,
她的坚韧 她的足智多谋	her tenacity, her resourcefulness.
但她还有另外一面	But there was another side to her,
大多数人从未看到的一面	a side most people never saw.
她精神中的那个部分让我们	It is that part of her spirit that has brought us
今晚聚集一堂	all together tonight.
马克欣是个矛盾人物	Max was something of a paradox.
她喜欢自相矛盾的东西	She had a fascination for paradoxes,
她把这一点遗传给了我	a fascination she passed on to me.
对于我们如今居住的这个世界 马克欣不存在幻想	Max had no illusions about the world we live in today.
但她梦想着打造不一样的未来	But she had dreams of a very different future.
在这样的未来里 将不再需要她的独特天赋	One in which her unique talents were no longer required.
她从现今的世界运转方式中 所赢得的一切	All she earned from the way the world is
都最终奉献给了 打造未来世界这一事业	went ultimately to making it what it could someday be.
那个未来尚未来临	That future isn't here yet.
今夜 你们的捐款让它距离我们 更近了一步	Tonight, your contributions have brought it just a little closer.
谢谢各位前来	Thank you all for coming.
畅享派对吧	Enjoy the party.
你不可能是约翰拉克	You can't possibly be John Lark.
事实上 我不是	I'm not, actually.
那是化名	It's an alias.
我想这个化名比无名氏要好	I suppose it's better than John Doe.
你更喜欢别的名字吗	Is there another name you prefer?
有地方可以让我们私下谈谈吗	Is there somewhere we could talk privately?
事实上 我喜欢拉克 听起来很响亮	In fact I like "Lark." It does have a certain ring.
时间不多了	We don't have a lot of time.
因为我会对你很坦白	'Cause I'll be honest.
你名声在外 我还以为	A man of your reputation, I was expecting someone
你会更难看一些	uglier.
别被外表所欺骗 我很残忍	Don't let looks deceive. I'm as ugly as they come.
恕我直言 你有生命危险	And I'll be honest with you. Your life is in danger.
不准碰她	Don't you touch her.
放轻松 他是我哥哥	Relax. It's my brother.
你对我们的客人很没礼貌 泽拉	You're being rude to our guest, Zola.
该走了	It's time to go.
别惹事	Don't turn this into a scene.
你最好别跟这家伙在一起	You don't want to be with this one.
-你刚才说什么来着 -你有生命危险	-You were saying? -Your life is in danger.
谁想杀我	And who would want to kill me?
首先 是美国人	The Americans, for starters.
如果真有其事 我会知道	If that were true, I would know it.
你以为你是唯一 在政府里安置间谍的人	You think you're the only one with spies in the government?
这里有人不希望我们见面	There are people here who don't want this meeting to happen.
不相信我	Don't believe me?
环顾四周	Look around.
我知道你在想什么	I know what you're thinking.
或许他们的目标不是你	Maybe they're not here for you.
或许他们的目标只是我	Maybe they're just here for me.
你愿意冒险吗	Are you willing to take that chance?
你有我想要的东西	You have something I want.
此时此刻 这让我成为 你唯一可以信任的人	Right now, that makes me the only person you can trust
能安全带你离开	to get you out of here alive.
抑或你想让你哥哥来处理此事	Or would you rather leave that to your brother?
我现在想回家了 拉克先生	I think I'd like to go home now, Mr. Lark.
法国政府今日中午接收了犯人	The French government took receipt of the asset at noon today.
将于明早八点通过空运	Delivery will be via air to the Finance Ministry
递送到财政部	at 8:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.
一支受警方严密保护的装甲车队	An armored motorcade under heavy police escort
将经由这条路线运送他	will transport him via this route.
我们会在这个十字路口使用障眼法 就是这里	We'll create a diversion at this intersection, here.
车队将自动采用预先安排的替代路线 行进到这里	The motorcade will automatically take the preplanned alternate route here,
我们会在那里劫走犯人	where we'll extract the asset.
劫走犯人	Extract the asset?
犯人	The asset.
我们花了大价钱才买到这份情报	We paid a great deal of money for this information.
除了此人的姓名 他们把其他情况都告诉了我们	They gave us everything but this man's name.
你不会碰巧知道他是谁吧	You don't happen to know who he is, do you?
他叫所罗门连恩	His name is Solomon Lane.
前英国特别探员 后来变成了无政府主义者	British Special Agent turned anarchist.
他利用叛变的秘密特工	He used rogue covert operatives
建立了一个叫辛迪加的恐怖网络	to create a terror network called the Syndicate.
蓄意破坏 暗杀 大屠杀	Sabotage, assassination, mass murder.
十恶不赦	As ugly as they come.
两年前 他被美国探员抓获	He was captured by American agents two years ago.
从那时起 他受到永无休止的审讯	Since then, he's been in a never-ending interrogation,
在政府之间来回辗转	passed around from one government to another
为他的罪行付出代价	to answer for his crimes.
你看起来很不开心 拉克	You seem displeased, Lark.
或许我没把话说清楚	Perhaps I didn't make myself clear.
我来巴黎是为了钚弹	I came to Paris for plutonium.
肯定是个误会	Well, there must be a misunderstanding.
我只是中间人	I'm just a broker.
我帮买家和卖家搭桥	I connect a buyer and a seller.
我的卖家对现金不感兴趣 所以如果你想要钚弹	My seller's not interested in cash, so if you want the plutonium...
截获连恩	Extract Lane
做交易	and make a trade.
没错	That's right.
我如何知道卖家手上有我的东西	How do I know the seller has what I want?
这是定金 为表诚意	A down payment in good faith.
送货人会在48小时内 递送剩下两枚钚弹	A courier will deliver two more within 48 hours
以交换他	in exchange for him.
好	All right.
使用障眼法之后怎么办	What happens after the diversion?
杀了所有人	Kill everyone?
这是你的计划	That's your plan?
不能有目击证人	There will be no witnesses.
你凭什么可以保证连恩的安全	What's my guarantee that Lane walks out of this thing alive?
他在装甲车里	He's in an armored box.
安全之后 我们才会把他弄出来	We'll pull him out when it's safe.
你想要你的钚弹	You want your plutonium,
这就是代价	this is the price.
抑或你不愿意跨越杀警察这一底线	Or do you draw the line at killing cops?
你的说话对象是约翰拉克	That's John Lark you're talking to.
我用天花杀害妇孺	I murder women and children with smallpox.
我没有底线	I have no line.
对	Right.
各位睡个好觉 明天会很忙	Sleep well, everyone. Busy day tomorrow.
开什么玩笑	You have got to be kidding me.
如果你想让连恩出狱 只能这么办	If you want Lane out of prison, this is how it gets done.
我希望拉克帮他越狱 不是伊森亨特	I wanted Lark to break him out, not Ethan Hunt.
我希望交换时拉克在场 不是伊森亨特	I wanted Lark at the exchange, not Ethan Hunt.
我希望拉克带我们找到钚弹	I wanted Lark to lead us to the plutonium
和使徒们	and the Apostles.
你或许依然有机会	You may still get your chance.
你忘了我们从大皇宫的男性洗手间里	Have you forgotten about the corpse we pulled
拉出来那具男尸	out of the men's room at the Grand Palais?
我猜那不是拉克	I'm guessing that wasn't Lark.
很有可能是拉克的手下人	More likely one of Lark's recruits.
根据我们的情报 不是的	Not according to our intelligence.
谁收集的情报	Intelligence gathered by whom?
亨特	Hunt.
你一直怀疑拉克是美国探员	You've long held suspicions that Lark was an American agent.
此人知道我们的所有行动	Someone who knew our every move.
来去无踪	Someone who could come and go like a ghost.
你暗示亨特就是约翰拉克	You're suggesting Hunt is John Lark.
你未免太牵强了 沃克 为了自保	You're reaching, Walker. Trying to save your ass.
不会起作用的	It won't work.
想一想 像拉克这样谨慎的人	Think about it. Would a man as careful as Lark
真的会冒那样的险	really stick his neck out like that?
就为了跟白寡妇见面	For a face-to-face with the White Widow?
-他会派替身去 -一个诱饵	-He'd send a proxy. -A decoy.
如果他真的很聪明	And if he was really smart,
他会让他的女朋友 在一个可靠的目击证人面前	he'd have his lady friend kill that decoy
杀掉那个诱饵	in front of a reliable witness.
就是我	Me.
天网恢恢 步步逼近他的恐怖分子化身	The dragnet is closing in on his terrorist alter ego.
所以他花钱请人假扮拉克	So he pays a man to play the part of Lark
然后找人干掉那个人	and has him killed.
利用他为国效命的伪装	And under the guise of serving his country...
使用他的秘密身份	Assumes his own secret identity.
在美国政府的	Free to operate at will
全力支持下 为所欲为	with the full support of the U.S. government.
为什么	Why?
亨特为什么会这样做	Why would Hunt turn?
连恩为什么这样做 他手下的使徒为什么会这么做	Why did Lane do it? Why did any of his Apostles?
他们相信一个目标	They were believers in a cause.
当那个目标变成谎言	And when that cause turned out to be a lie,
他们与自己的主人反目	they turned against their masters.
亨特的政府背叛 否认和抛弃他	How many times has Hunt's government betrayed him,
多少次了	disavowed him, cast him aside?
这样的人多久之后	And how long before a man like that
会忍无可忍	has had enough?
这是一项严厉的指控	That is a serious accusation.
你能证明吗	Can you prove it?
这是我们从大皇宫那具男尸身上	This is the phone we pulled off the dead body
拿来的手机	at the Grand Palais.
我猜想这上面有你需要的所有证据	I'm guessing it has all the proof you need.
连恩对一个有两千人口的村子 释放毒气 此事属实吗	Is it true Lane gassed a village of 2,000 people?
是的	Yes.
为了杀害一个人 他不惜让整座客机坠毁	Is it true he brought down an entire passenger plane
此事属实吗	just to kill one man?
是的	Yes.
-此事属实吗他 -嘿 沃克	-Is it true that he... -Hey, Walker.
你听到的任何事 如果让你毛骨悚然	Whatever you heard, if it makes your skin crawl,
很有可能是真的	it's probably true.
老天	Holy shit.
他是被你抓到的 对吗	You're the guy that caught him, aren't you?
你认为	How long do you think
他对此事会隐瞒多久呢	he's gonna keep that to himself?
到时候再说	We'll burn that bridge when we get to it.
他到底在干什么	What the hell is he doing?
（没有信号）
亨特你在哪	Hunt? Where are you?
别等我 	Don't wait for me!
怎么了出什么事了	What is it? What's wrong?
我会在车库等你	I'll meet you at the garage.
班吉 你收到了吗	Benji, do you copy?
我们收到了 快走	We copy. Go.
改变计划 我曝光了 需要撤离	Change of plan. I'm blown. Need extraction.
我们马上过来	We're on our way.
他从巴黎圣母院驶往圣路易斯桥	He's heading from Notre Dame to the St. Louis bridge.
各单位在追捕	Units are in pursuit...
停下	STOP.
不许动	Stay where you are.
上车	Get in the car.
谁都不许动	Nobody move.
举起手来	Show me your hands.
请走开	Walk away...please.
所有人举起手来	Everyone...show me your hands.
请走开	Just walk away...
拜托	please.
泽拉想跟你谈谈	Zola wants a word with you.
她怎么办	What about her?
干掉她	Finish her.
你会没事的	You'll be all right.
我们得走了	We got to go.
真的很抱歉	I'm so sorry.
来吧	Come on.
对了 我叫沃克	The name's Walker, by the way.
用这辆小车是你的主意	Was the little car your idea?
老天爷 	Jesus Christ!
刚才是怎么回事	What the hell was that?
-大家马上下车  -快 	-Everybody out. -Go, go, go!
那是艾尔莎	That was Ilsa.
闭嘴	Shut up.
真有意思	Very interesting.
很高兴再次见到你 伊森	It's good to see you again, Ethan.
哦 看看谁还活着	Oh, look who's still alive.
他的脖子里有个微波追踪器	There's a microwave tracker in his neck.
明白了 你知道该怎么办	Got it. You know what to do.
我跟你保证 这不会	Let me just assure you, this won't hurt
太痛	enough.
90秒	Ninety seconds.
你和你的使徒们认为 我们会用你	You and your Apostles think we're gonna trade you
来交换丢失的钚弹	for the missing plutonium.
我在此告诉你 这件事绝不可能发生	I'm here to tell you that's never gonna happen.
你的任务 如果你选择接受	Your mission, should you choose to accept it.
我想知道 伊森	I wonder, Ethan,
你是否曾经选择过不接受	did you ever choose not to?
你是否曾经停下来 扪心自问	Did you ever stop and ask yourself
谁给你命令或是为什么	who it was giving you the orders or why?
每一天 你为之效命的主人 都距离毁灭世界更近一步	While every day the master you serve moves one step closer to ending the world.
恐怖分子做出的怪异指控	Strange accusation coming from a terrorist.
60秒	Sixty seconds.
恐怖分子是极度渴望关注的年轻学生	Terrorists are schoolboys desperate for attention,
希望通过恐惧来塑造公众观点	hoping to shape public opinion through fear.
我根本不在乎人们的想法和感受	I don't care in the least what people think or feel.
就我的经验来说 他们的想法和感受都不会持续很久	In my experience, they don't do either for very long.
我猜想这能为你轰炸工厂 和炸毁民航飞机的罪行	Oh, and I suppose that justifies bombing factories
做出开脱	or bringing down civilian aircraft.
或是给我绑上装有炸药的背心 	Or strapping me into an explosive vest!
就当这是未了之事吧 我滑稽的小朋友	Consider it unfinished business, my funny little friend.
-卢瑟 -马上就好了	-Luther? -Almost there.
关于结局 你看得跟我一样清楚 伊森	You see the end as clearly as I do, Ethan.
世界各地的政府正陷入疯狂	Governments the world over are descending into madness.
辛迪加的创建目的 是为了一砖一瓦地将其摧毁	The Syndicate was created to tear them down, brick by brick.
辛迪加是一群杀人成性的懦夫	The Syndicate was a pack of murdering cowards.
辛迪加是文明的最后希望 	The Syndicate was civilization's last hope!
摧毁老旧世界秩序的机会	A chance to smash the old world order.
现在这份希望破灭了 因为你	That hope is gone now because of you
和你可悲的道德观	and your pathetic morality.
你应该杀了我的 伊森	You should have killed me, Ethan.
你向来惧怕的结局	The end you've always feared
即将来临	is coming.
即将来临 	It's coming!
一切都是你的罪过	And the blood will be on your hands.
你美好企图	The fallout
的附带后果	of all your good intentions.
-时间到了 -搞定了	-Time. -Got it.
把他拉起来	Get him up.
你现在归我所有了	You're mine now.
你真是充满惊喜 拉克	You're just full of surprises, Lark.
你哥哥的计划从一开始起就很烂	Your brother's plan was bad from the word go.
你的手下人可能都会没命	You'd have lost all your men
连恩在交火中也有可能丧命	and Lane would've been killed in the crossfire.
我得随机应变	I had to improvise.
为何最开始不说	Well, why not say that in the first place?
因为我不信任你的人	Because I don't trust your people.
特别是你哥哥	Especially not your brother.
家人 能怎么办	Family. What can you do?
那么 连恩在哪	So, where's Lane?
肯定不在塞纳河底	Certainly not at the bottom of the Seine.
他在我手上 他很安全	I have him. He's safe.
我在哪里跟送货人见面	Where do I meet the courier?
我们来谈谈那个女人吧	Let's talk about the woman.
女人	Woman?
你在大皇宫时 她跟你在一起	She was with you at the Palais.
泽拉今天又看到她了	Zola saw her again today.
她企图杀死连恩	She tried to kill Lane.
她有机会杀你 却没下手	She had the chance to kill you, but she didn't.
为什么	Why?
我们曾经有过一段	We have a past.
很复杂	It's complicated.
好吧 我会让事情变得更复杂	Well, I'll make it more complicated for you.
我的价码刚刚涨了	My price just went up.
今天有人杀了我四个手下人	Someone killed four of my men today.
我猜想是她干的	I'm assuming it was her.
我想要她 拉克	I want her, Lark.
你要把她带给我	And you're gonna bring her to me.
否则 你不会跟送货人见面	Otherwise, you don't meet the courier
钚弹会卖给出价最高的人	and the plutonium goes to the highest bidder.
我可不想她坏了我们的好事	I'd hate for her to come between us.
我会把她交给你	She's yours.
在见面时 之前不行	At the meeting. Not before.
去伦敦	Go to London.
遵照指示	Instructions will follow.
我知道如果我跟踪她 你最终会现身	I knew if I followed her, you'd show up eventually.
你没事吧	Are you okay?
艾尔莎 我从未想过要伤害你	Ilsa, I never wanted to hurt you.
我知道你有自己的理由	I know you have your reasons.
我知道	I know.
你需要放弃这项任务	You need to walk away.
办不到	I can't do that.
你去大皇宫不是为了杀拉克	You weren't at the Palais to kill Lark.
对	No.
你去那里保护他	You were there to protect him.
是的	Yes.
你杀了他是为了保护我	And you killed him to protect me.
你希望拉克帮连恩越狱	You wanted Lark to break Lane out.
不 你需要他帮连恩越狱	No. You needed him to break Lane out.
因为你必须杀死连恩	Because you have to kill Lane.
谁逼你这么做	Who's making you do this?
军情六处	MI6.
为什么	Why?
我们在伦敦抓到他之后	After we captured him in London,
他们试图通过外交渠道 把连恩送回英国	they tried to bring Lane home through diplomatic channels.
但很多国家都想复仇	But too many countries want their pound of flesh.
那样的人 对于英国情报	A man like that, what he's seen,
他的所见和所知	what he knows about British Intelligence,
他们绝不能让他跟外国政府交谈	they can't have him talking to a foreign government ever.
我问的不是这个问题	That's not what I'm asking.
他们为何派你来	Why did they send you?
我通过这种方式证明我的忠诚	This is how I prove my loyalty.
这样我才可以回家	This is how I come home.
但你退役了	But you were out.
你自由了	You were free.
我们永远不会自由	We are never free.
我花了两年时间 跟连恩做卧底工作	I spent two years undercover with Lane.
对他们来说 我跟他的威胁度一样大	To them, I'm as much of a threat as he is.
我要杀死他 否则我会永远逃亡	I kill him, or I never stop running.
现在 告诉我他在哪里	Now tell me where he is.
我没法帮你	I can't help you.
无论如何 我都会抓到他	I will get to him one way or another.
请别逼我跟你作对	Please don't make me go through you.
是的	Yes.
你在伦敦吗	Are you here in London?
是的	I am.
你准备好跟送货人见面了吗	Are you ready to meet the courier?
是的 我要去哪里	Yes. Where do I go?
你想在哪里见面	Where would you like to meet?
（查找来电者位置）
秘书长先生	Mr. Secretary.
我对天祈祷 但愿这不是真的	I prayed to God that it wasn't true.
长官 以伊森的立场来说	Well, in his defense, sir,
如果他没有干预	if Ethan hadn't intervened,
很多人会送命	a great many people would have been killed.
对 邓恩 我确信巴黎的好市民	Yes, Dunn, I'm sure that the good people of Paris
和法国整个国家会考虑到这一点	and the nation of France as a whole will take that into account.
所以到底发生了什么事	So what the hell happened?
当时 我们被告知要来伦敦	...at which point, we were told to come to London
等待进一步指示	and await further instructions.
现在怎么办	And what happens now?
现在	Now,
我们20分钟后跟白寡妇见面	we meet the Widow in 20 minutes.
她会带我们去见送货人	She'll take us to a courier
送货人会用我们丢失的钚弹 来交换所罗门连恩	who'll hand over our missing plutonium in exchange for Solomon Lane.
或者根据我们的行动方案	Or, in our scenario,
班吉	Benji.
老天	Jesus.
抱歉 你说什么	I'm sorry, what?
卢瑟和我会带你去见送货人	Luther and I are gonna take you to the courier.
沃克留在这里 看守真正的连恩	Walker stays here and guards the real Lane.
绝对不行	Absolutely not.
等等 为何一定要我假扮连恩	Wait, wait. Why do I have to be Lane?
班吉	Benji.
我们的任务 我的任务 是重新拿回钚弹	Our mission, my mission, is to recover that plutonium,
我会不惜一切达成目的	and I will do so at any cost.
就算我得用连恩来交换	Even if I have to trade Lane.
真正的连恩	The real Lane.
我绝不会放他走	And I will never let him go.
当使徒们意识到你在玩游戏	When the Apostles realize that you're playing games,
你会再次失去钚弹	you'll lose the plutonium. Again.
你让我们来操心使徒吧	You let us worry about the Apostles.
就目前的情况来说 我们面临一个更大的问题	As it stands, we have a bigger problem.
更大的问题	A bigger problem?
-艾尔莎 -艾尔莎	-Ilsa. -Ilsa?
我们的艾尔莎艾尔莎浮士德	Our Ilsa? Ilsa Faust Ilsa?
她怎么会卷入此事	How is she mixed up in all of this?
她受命要杀死连恩 直接来自军情六处的命令	She's been ordered to kill Lane. Direct from MI6.
听着 等等 在巴黎那个人是她 骑摩托车那个	Look, wait. So that was her in Paris? On the bike.
对	Yeah.
伊森 她企图杀死我们 	Ethan, she tried to kill us!
-不 不是我们 -对	-No, not us. Not us. -Yeah.
连恩 她企图杀死连恩 她没得选	Lane. She tried to kill Lane. She has no choice.
她会杀死我 	And she will kill me!
我不会让这种事发生	I'm not gonna let that happen.
伊森 你打算怎样阻止此事的发生	Ethan, how exactly are you not gonna let that happen?
-我在想办法 -他在想办法	-I'm working on it. -Oh, he's working on it.
目前 我们没时间了	Right now, we don't have a lot of time.
我们必须为碰面做好准备	We have to get ready for this meeting.
会面是个陷阱	The meeting is a trap.
白寡妇跟中情局联手	The White Widow is working with the CIA.
从一开始起 她就这样做了	She has been since the beginning.
为了讨价还价 赦免她的各种罪行	Bargaining for immunity is her stock-in-trade.
拿到钚弹并抓获使徒和约翰拉克	Capturing the plutonium, and the Apostles, and John Lark
会让她从美国人那里博得不少好感	buys her a lot of goodwill with the Americans.
如果斯隆知道这次会面是陷阱 她为何不告诉我们	But if Sloane knew the meeting was a trap, why didn't she just tell us?
因为在她看来 任何人都有可能是约翰拉克	Because, in her mind, anybody could be John Lark,
包括我们中的人	including one of us.
现在她的怀疑获得了证实	And now her suspicions are confirmed.
根据那份卷宗	According to that dossier,
电子证据留下的蛛丝马迹将亨特	a trail of electronic evidence connects Hunt
和疾病控制与预防中心的天花失窃案 联系起来	to the theft of smallpox from the CDC.
也将他跟一段冗长的邮件来往 联系在一起	It also links him to a lengthy correspondence
最终事宜是招募德尔布鲁克博士	ending with the recruitment of Dr. Delbruuk.
当然了 亨特亲自将钚弹	And, of course, Hunt handed over the plutonium
交给了使徒	to the Apostles himself.
那些事实 外加	Now, those facts, coupled with
一段长期且有犯罪嫌疑的 叛变行为历史	a long and incriminating history of rogue behavior,
证实了中情局的说法	corroborate a CIA narrative
亨特已经失控了	that Hunt has snapped.
寻找拉克只是他的障眼法	And that his search for Lark is nothing but a cover
为了隐藏这个事实 拉克	to hide the fact that Lark...
就是我	...is me.
我真是服了你了 伊森	I've got to hand it to you, Ethan.
通常情况下 人们说你是你自己最大的敌人	Normally, when people refer to you as your own worst enemy,
只是个比喻	it's just a figure of speech.
恐怕斯隆对她也有一些疑问	I'm afraid Sloane's got some questions for her as well.
白寡妇提出把她交给中情局 无需另行收费	The Widow offered her up at no extra charge.
斯隆从哪里获得这条信息的	And where did Sloane get this information?
她没说	She didn't say.
不过 她给我机会抓你	She did, however, grant me the opportunity to bring you in,
条件是我要终止本次任务	on the condition that I terminate this mission
亲自交付所罗门连恩	and hand over Solomon Lane personally.
-长官 你不能这么做 -亨特	-Sir, you can't do that. -Hunt.
我了解连恩 他根本不想重返监狱	I know Lane. And he has no intention of going back.
所以我们会带他回去	That's why we're taking him back.
这表示他就想我们这么做	Which means that's exactly what he wants us to do.
-伊森 -先生 你认为	-Ethan... -Sir, what do you
这是怎么回事巧合吗	think this is? A coincidence?
有人碰巧发现了这份卷宗	That someone just happened upon this?
连恩派人送给她的 他知道她会做出怎样的反应	Lane had it sent to her. He knew how she would react.
正如他知道 白寡妇会把我们交给中情局	Just like he knew the Widow would turn us in.
你不明白吗	Don't you see?
这个 长官	This, sir...
这是陷阱	This is the trap.
-我们被人误导了 -亨特 	-We are being directed. -Hunt!
还有两枚钚弹下落不明 	There are still two plutonium cores in the wind!
是你弄丢的 	And you lost them!
说句公道话 长官 是我们弄丢的	In fairness, sir, we all lost them.
我恭敬地说一句 长官 你当时不在场	Respectfully, sir, you weren't there.
替他找借口 是你们现在的全职工作吗	So making excuses for him is your full-time job now?
天哪 伊森 别雪上加霜	Good God, Ethan, don't make this any harder than it already is.
我没法继续保护你了 你不明白吗	I can no longer protect you, don't you understand that?
你对钚弹只能做到这一步了	This is as close as you're ever gonna get to that plutonium.
长官 你不会真的相信吧	Sir, you don't actually believe this.
我相信我要在保护你	I believe I've been given a choice to protect you
或不可能任务小组之间做出选择 我会逮捕你	or the IMF, which is why I'm bringing you in.
如果我拒绝呢	And if I refuse?
你以为他的作用是什么	What do you think he's here for?
你以为他只是旁观者	You think he's some observer?
他是杀手 	He's an assassin!
艾丽卡斯隆清理门户的头号探员	Erika Sloane's number-one plumber.
如果你叛变 他有权追捕你	You go rogue, he's authorized to hunt you down
然后干掉你	and kill you.
是本职工作 别往心里去	It's the job. No hard feelings.
接受吧 伊森	Accept it, Ethan.
这次行动你失败了 木已成舟	You've lost this one. What's done is done.
不 长官 不	No, sir. No.
我不是在问你 我在直接命令你	I am not asking you. I am giving you a direct order.
本次任务被终止了	This mission is terminated.
立即生效 	Now!
斯蒂克尔 他是你的朋友	Stickell, he's your friend.
你能否开导他一下	Would you please talk some sense into...
抱歉 长官 你让我没得选	I'm sorry, sir, but you left me no choice.
距离我们见白寡妇 还有15分钟	There's 15 minutes before we meet the Widow.
你想要钚弹 只有我们才能	You want the plutonium, we're the only ones
帮你拿到 你到底要不要加入	who can get it for you. You in or out?
我加入	In.
-你在干什么 -班吉需要做好准备	-What are you doing? -Benji needs to get ready.
-不 伊森 -没时间了 卢瑟	-No, Ethan... -There's no time, Luther.
我需要你信任我	I need you to trust me.
你没事吧	You all right?
嗯 我只是	Yeah, I just
对此事有不祥的预感	got a bad feeling about this one.
如果你没有我们的消息	If you don't hear from us...
我会自行处理	I'll do it my way.
好好盯着他	Don't take your eyes off him.
游戏玩够了 我带你出去	Enough games. I'm taking you out of here.
亨特在哪	Where's Hunt?
他带你的替身去跟人见面了	He's gone to the meeting, with a copy of you.
冷静点	Calm down.
打给使徒 警告他们	Call the Apostles. Warn them.
我没办法联络他们	I have no way of contacting them.
为了他们和我自己的安全	For their safety and mine.
我有一支撤离小队	What I do have is an extraction team with
有卫星监测和事先安排好的见面地点	satellite overwatch and a prearranged rendezvous.
我们一离开大楼 他们就会知道	They'll know as soon as we leave the building.
不 我会留在这里	No, I'm staying here.
我跟亨特之间还没完	I haven't finished with Hunt yet.
你干嘛把这件事搞得如此复杂	Why did you have to make this so fucking complicated?
我不明白你的意思	I don't understand what you mean.
交易很简单	The deal was simple.
我帮你陷害亨特 你把钚弹给我	I help you frame Hunt, you give me the plutonium.
你在浪费时间	You're wasting time.
不经受巨大苦难 绝不会有和平	There cannot be peace without first a great suffering.
苦难越深重 和平就越伟大	The greater the suffering, the greater the peace.
我写下这些话的时候	When I wrote those words,
意思不是你的和平或亨特的苦难	I wasn't referring to your peace or Hunt's suffering.
旧的世界秩序需要废除	The old world order needs dismantling,
我们有废除它的工具	and we have the tools to dismantle it.
你好像只在乎	All you seem to care about
亨特能活命 当替罪羔羊	is that Hunt lives to take the blame.
那不是无政府状态	That's not anarchy.
那是报复	That's revenge.
没错	Yes, it is.
当我达到自己的目的	And when I have what I want,
使徒就会把钚弹给你	the Apostles will give you the plutonium.
亨特是你唯一的朋友	Hunt's the only friend you've got.
你能活到今天	You're only alive today
是因为他没胆杀你	because he didn't have the guts to kill you.
斯隆说得对 不可能任务小组就是万圣节闹剧	Sloane was right. The IMF is Halloween.
只是成年人戴	Nothing but grown men wearing...
怎么	What?
本职工作而已 别往心里去	It's just the job. No hard feelings.
我毁了你的好日子 不是吗	I've ruined your day, haven't I?
到刚才之前 你表现得真好	And you were doing so well up until then.
我觉得这把枪里才装有子弹	Now, I think this one's loaded.
你想弄清楚吗	You want to find out?
-我表现得怎么样 -我从未怀疑过你的能力	-So, how'd I do? -I never had a doubt.
我开始明白你们为何乐在其中了	I'm beginning to see why you guys enjoy this so much.
恭喜你 秘书长先生	Hats off, Mr. Secretary.
-他是天生好手 -欢迎你加入团队 长官	-The man's a natural. -Welcome to the team, sir.
你们在犯错	You're making a mistake.
不 我在巴黎上空救了你一命 犯了大错	No, the mistake was mine when I saved your life over Paris.
这没法证明任何东西 我在演戏	This proves nothing. I'm playing a role,
跟你们一样 目的是为了重新拿回钚弹	just like you are, trying to recover that plutonium.
这没法解释你为何将那个卷宗 交给斯隆	That doesn't explain why you gave Sloane the dossier
企图陷害亨特	and tried to frame Hunt.
他说得很有道理	He makes a good point,
拉克	Lark.
他是偏执狂 有妄想症	He's paranoid. Delusional.
正如卷宗里所说的那样	Just like the dossier says.
斯隆是从哪里获得那个卷宗的	So where did Sloane get the dossier from?
我不知道	I have no idea.
我知道	I do.
你都看到了吗 艾丽卡	Did you get all that, Erika?
是的	I did.
我可不喜欢被人利用 沃克	I don't appreciate being used, Walker.
坏小子	Bad boy.
你想把他送去哪里	Where would you like him delivered?
我会过来找你们	I'll come to you.
都不许动 	Nobody move! Nobody move!
放下武器 放下 	Weapons down! Drop 'em!
举起手来 放下武器 	Hands in the air! Weapons down!
放下武器 	Drop it! Drop it!
马上放下武器 你 	Weapons down! Right now! You!
没关系 没事的	It's okay. It's okay. It's all right.
我以为我们说好了	I thought we had a deal.
之前是的 现在不是了	We did. And now we don't.
风险太大 我不能冒险	There is too much at stake here for me to take any chances.
我会逮捕你们所有人 包括沃克	I'm bringing you all in, along with Walker.
钚弹依然下落不明 	The plutonium is still out there!
拿回钚弹这项任务 我不相信那个房间里的任何人	And I don't trust a living soul in that room to get it.
我们会在华府查明谁才靠得住	We'll sort out who's who in Washington.
-艾丽卡  -长官	-Erika! -Sir?
没关系 照她的话做吧	It's all right. Let's just do what she says.
唯一真正的威胁在这个房间里 他们在我们手上	The only real threats are in this room, and we have them.
是吗	Do you?
开始行动	Go.
连恩到底在哪	Where the hell is Lane?
伊森 	Ethan! Ethan!
第一小队都死了 派增援过来	First team is down. Send backup.
长官 	Sir!
不 有人受伤了 	Oh, no, no, no. Man down! Man down!
快来人帮忙 	Somebody help!
长官	Sir.
伊森 我在沃克身上装了追踪器 但他逃跑了	Ethan, I tagged Walker, but he's on the run.
你得去抓他	You got to get him.
快去	Go.
对不起 长官	I'm sorry, sir.
伊森	Ethan?
等等 	Wait!
抓到那个混蛋	Get that son of a bitch.
快点	Come on, come on, come on.
太好了 我找到他了	Yes! I got him.
抱歉	I'm sorry.
跟我说话 班吉 沃克在哪	Talk to me, Benji. Where's Walker?
如果你向右转 他在西边约400米处	He's about a quarter mile west  if you turn right.
我的右边	To my right?
不行	I can't do that.
为何不行	Why not?
因为我被人跟踪	Because I'm being followed.
什么意思被谁跟踪	What do you mean? By who?
我怎么知道中情局 使徒	How do I know? CIA, Apostles...
有何区别	What difference does it make?
好吧 从那里出去 然后右转	Okay, okay, just get out of there and then go right.
真的很抱歉	I am terribly sorry.
告辞了	Excuse me.
他干嘛在跑圈子	Why is he running in circles?
（往上）
好 你需要尽快穿过你左边街道	Okay, you need to cross the street on your left as soon as you can.
伊森 你收到了吗	Ethan, did you copy?
-左边 马上往左走  -我正在努力	-Left, go left, now! -I'm working on it.
现在穿过你正前方的街道	Now go across the street right in front of you.
伊森 他正离你远去 你得加快速度	Ethan, he's getting away from you! You're gonna have to go faster.
你快追上他了 往前走	You're gaining on him! Go straight.
往前继续往前	Straight? Keep going straight?
往前 继续往前	Go straight, go straight, straight, straight.
好的 现在向右转	Okay, now turn right.
右边	Right?
现在吗	Now?
-对 右边  -你确信吗	-Yes, right! -Are you sure?
是的 我	Yes, I'm...
不 是左边 向左转 	No, it's left! Turn left!
抱歉 我启用了屏幕锁定	Sorry, I had the screen-lock on.
左边	Left.
谢谢	Thank you.
-你在等什么 -我要跳窗 	-What are you waiting for? -I'm jumping out a window!
你说跳窗是什么意思	What do you mean, you're jumping out of a...
抱歉 我的屏幕是2D画面	Oh, sorry. I had it in 2D.
祝好运	Good luck.
在桥的末端向左转 你马上就要追上他了	At the end of the bridge, turn left. You've almost got him.
加油 伊森 抓住他 	Come on, come on, come on. Come on, Ethan, get him!
你就在他的后面 	You're right on top of him!
对了 他就在你的前面 	That's it, he's right in front of you!
抓住他 	Get him! Get him! Get him!
你不能杀我 对吗 在拿到钚弹之前不行	You can't do it, can you? Not until you get your plutonium.
不 他对你还有计划	No. He still has plans for you.
你要自首 承认自己是约翰拉克	You're gonna turn yourself in and admit you're John Lark,
从你狭小黑暗的牢房里 看着旧世界瓦解	then watch the old world implode from your dark little cell.
如果我不这样做呢	And if I don't?
我是她的守护天使 亨特	I'm her guardian angel, Hunt.
如果我再看到你 她会死	If I see you again, she dies.
如果你试图警告她 她会死	If you try to warn her, she dies.
要明白你已经失败了	Know when you're beat.
这是我们从德尔布鲁克博士在柏林的 实验室里发现的设计图	These are the designs we recovered from Dr. Delbruuk's lab in Berlin.
那是一个五兆吨重的核设备	That's a five-megaton nuclear device.
比二战时释放的所有爆炸能量	That's greater than all the explosive energy
都要强大	released in World War II.
我们通常会剪断这里的保险丝 就可以拆除炸弹	To disarm it, normally we'd cut the fuse wire here.
什么 通常	What, "normally"?
沃克和连恩手上有两枚钚弹	Walker and Lane have two plutonium cores,
也就是两枚炸弹	meaning two bombs.
对 它们都跟一个 微波自动防故障装置相连接	Yeah. And they're both linked by a microwave fail-safe
精确度小于十分之一秒	which is accurate to within one-tenth of a second.
只要企图拆除一枚炸弹 都会引爆另一枚炸弹	Any attempt to defuse one bomb automatically triggers the other.
这表示炸弹一旦做好发射准备 就不能解除	Meaning once armed, the bombs cannot be disarmed.
倒计时由一个遥控引爆器触发	The countdown is started by a remote detonator,
这个引爆器也是自动防故障装置	which is also a fail-safe.
表示倒计时一旦开始	Meaning once the countdown starts,
就没法阻止	it can't be stopped.
那么解决方案是什么	So the solution to this is?
我们正在想办法	We're working on it.
那么	So,
严格说来 这是绝命行动	technically, this is a suicide mission.
怎么了	What is it?
请坐	Have a seat. Please.
我认识伊森这么多年	In all the years that I've known Ethan,
他只对两个女人认真过	he's only been serious about two women.
其中一个是他的妻子	One was his wife.
他结婚了	He's married?
不 他曾经结过婚	No, he was.
曾经她怎么了	Was? What happened to her?
一些想抓伊森的人	Well, she was taken
绑架了她	by some people who wanted to get to Ethan.
没关系 他把她平安救回来了	It's okay, he got her back in one piece.
然后他退隐江湖	Then he quit the game.
他们度过了一段幸福时光	They were happy for a while.
但每次世界上发生坏事	But every time something bad happened in the world,
伊森就觉得自己应该去那里	Ethan would think, "I should've been there."
她会想如果伊森保护我	And she would wonder, "Who's watching the world
谁来保护世界	while Ethan's watching me?
内心深处 他们都知道 某一天 出于某种原因	Deep down, they both knew that someday, somehow,
会发生真正恐怖的事情	something truly terrible was going to happen
就是因为他们在一起	all because they were together.
所以	So...
-她现在在哪里 -她销声匿迹	-Where is she now? -She's a ghost.
她也擅长此道	Good at it, too.
我亲自教她的	Taught her myself.
她时不时会发送信号	Every now and then, she sends up a signal
告诉伊森她平安无事	to let Ethan know she's safe.
这让他有不断前进的勇气	And that keeps him going.
你为何告诉我这些	Why are you telling me this?
我们身处这团乱麻之中 就是因为伊森不想让我丧命	We're in this mess because Ethan wouldn't let me die.
他是个好人	He's a good man.
他很关心你 虽然他嘴上不说	And he cares about you more than he can admit.
他现在不能担心这件事	That's one more worry than he can handle right now.
如果你关心他	If you care about him,
你应该走开	you should walk away.
卢瑟	Luther...
一切还好吧	Is everything all right?
我跟你一起去	I'm coming with you.
我知道	I know.
我们如何找到他	So how do we find him?
微波转发器	Microwave transponder.
在世上任何地方 通过卫星都可以追踪到	Traceable via satellite anywhere in the world.
连恩的脖子后面有一个这样的转发器	Lane had one of these in the back of his neck.
我们在巴黎把它拿掉了	We removed it in Paris.
与此同时 我们放置了自己的转发器	At the same time, we put our own transponder in.
搞定了	Got it.
延迟36小时启动	36-hour delayed activation,
以防连恩的使徒对他进行扫描	in case Lane's Apostles scan him.
所以你们计划好了要放他走	So you planned on letting him go.
不是通过这种方式 不过的确如此	Not this way, but yes.
他会引导我们找到钚弹	He's gonna lead us to the plutonium.
你们如何能确定	How can you be sure?
他送我进监狱这个计划泡汤了	His plan to put me in prison went to hell.
现在他希望我去那里看到炸弹引爆	Now he's gonna want me there for the end.
这个转发器何时会启动	So when does this transponder activate?
我找到他了 	I got him. I got him, I got him, I got him!
他正以每小时500节的速度 在欧洲上空行驶	He's traveling east over Europe at 500 knots.
他在坐飞机	He's airborne.
我们应该通知中情局吗	Shall we inform the CIA?
中情局被人渗透了	The CIA's been infiltrated.
我只相信这个房间里的人	I don't trust anybody outside of this room.
我们必须单独行动	We're gonna have to go it alone.
那我们要去那里	So where do we go?
（克什米尔）
怎么样了 班吉	How we doing, Benji?
如果有拆除炸弹的方法 我却找不到	If there's a way to defuse these bombs, I can't find it.
你会搞清楚的 我知道你会	You'll figure it out. I know you will.
该死 伊森 我们失去信号了	Damn. Ethan, we lost the signal.
连恩肯定发现我们的传输器了	Lane must've found our transmitter.
-他的最后位置在哪里 -东北方向约48公里处	-What's his last position? -About 30 miles northeast.
那么他希望我们去那里	Then that's where he wants us to go.
-那里是什么地方 -努布拉河河谷	-What's there? -The Nubra River Valley.
那里只有一个医疗营	There's only a medical camp there.
海外人道主义援助小组	Humanitarian Aid Overseas.
连恩为何以医疗营为目标	Why would Lane target a medical camp?
天花	Smallpox.
什么	What?
天花 使徒在克什米尔 引发了天花疫情的爆发	Smallpox. The Apostles triggered a smallpox outbreak in Kashmir.
连恩以那座营地为目标 肯定有其原因	Lane must've wanted that camp there for a reason.
不过是什么原因	But what?
-天哪 -怎么了	-Oh, my God. -What is it?
努布拉河位于锡亚琴冰川的底部	The Nubra River is at the base of the Siachen Glacier.
所以如果那里发生核武器爆炸	So a nuclear blast there would irradiate
会使世上最大的天然灌溉系统 遭受核辐射	the largest natural irrigation system in the world.
来自中国到印度 及巴基斯坦边境的淡水	Fresh water from the border of China to India and Pakistan.
他们会让世上三分之一的人口挨饿	They're gonna starve one-third of the world's population.
苦难越深重	The greater the suffering...
和平就越伟大	...the greater the peace.
我还是不明白 连恩为何以那里的医疗营为目标	I still don't understand why Lane wants a medical camp there.
这不重要	It doesn't matter.
现在重要的是 找到拆除那些炸弹的方法	All that matters now is we find a way to defuse those bombs.
我想我找到了	I think I've found it.
或许吧	Maybe.
看 炸弹的操作系统 好像存在一个漏洞	Look, there appears to be a flaw in the bomb's operating system.
遥控引爆器需要那个引爆按钮	The remote detonator requires that firing key.
如果我们除掉那个按钮 应该会	If we remove that key, then it should short out
使自动防故障装置短路 让我们剪断两枚炸弹的保险丝	the fail-safe and allow us to cut both fuses.
所以我们其中一人要拿到引爆器	So one of us needs to get the detonator
移除那个按钮	and remove that key.
对	Yeah.
其他人要剪断两枚炸弹的保险丝 很简单	While the rest of us cut the fuses on both bombs. Simple.
对 不过	Yeah, but...
不过什么	But what?
为了让这个方法成功	Well, in order to make this work,
只有倒计时开始之后	we can't remove the key or cut the fuses
我们才能移除按钮或剪断保险丝	until after the countdown starts.
不过等等 让我把事情理清楚	But wait, just so I've got this clear.
我们安全拆除两枚炸弹的唯一机会	Our only chance to safely defuse both bombs
就是让倒计时开始	is to let the countdown start.
然后移除那个按钮	And then remove that key.
好	Okay.
现在两个设备都已经与引爆器相连	Both devices are now connected to the detonator.
15分钟应该足够让你	Fifteen minutes should give you enough time
到达最低安全距离	to reach minimum safe distance.
我的逃亡生涯结束了	My running days are over.
这里是我的最终归属	This is where it ends for me.
到处都有信号	I'm getting signals all over the place.
我们在医疗营 到处都有X光机 电脑断层扫描仪	We're at a medical camp. X-ray machines, CAT scanners,
和放射性信号	radiological signatures everywhere.
就好像海底捞针	It's like a needle in a haystack.
用排除法 逐个排除	Process of elimination, one at a time.
分头行动 保持通讯	Let's split up. Stay on comms.
（海外人道主义援助小组）
伊森	Ethan?
朱莉娅	Julia?
那是	Is that...
朱莉娅 	Julia!
他知道吗	Does he know?
嘿	Hey.
这是我老公埃里克	This is my husband, Erik.
这是	This is...
罗伯 罗伯索恩 罗伯索恩医生	Rob. Rob Thorne. Dr. Rob Thorne.
-我曾经跟朱莉娅共事 -在麻省总医院	-I worked with Julia... -At Mass General.
在我搬去纽约之前	Before New York.
开玩笑吧	Oh, you're kidding.
-真巧  -我知道 我	-What a coincidence! -I know. I...
-你大老远跑这里来干什么 -我	-What brings you all this way? -I was...
我在离此地不远的特图克	I was in Turtuk, not far from here
听说这里需要帮手	and heard help was needed.
那好	Oh, well,
事实上 我们在这里差不多完事了	actually we're just about finished here.
整个村子的人都打了预防针 不过	The whole village is inoculated. But...
你在特图克干什么	What were you doing out in Turtuk?
罗伯在休假	Rob's on vacation.
不 我我在工作	No. No, I'm... I'm working.
你远离家园	You're a long way from home.
对 多亏了我们的守护天使	Yeah, yeah. Thanks to our guardian angel.
守护	Guardian?
对 当这里爆发天花疫情时	Well, yeah. We were running a field hospital
我们正在达尔富尔郊外 运营一家野战医院	outside of Darfur when the outbreak happened here.
出乎意料的是	And here comes this phone call
一位匿名捐赠人打电话给我们	from an anonymous donor, out of the blue.
他说他愿意承担	And he says he's ready to underwrite
整个运营的费用 有一个条件	the entire operation. One condition.
我们负责运营	We run the whole thing.
你相信吗	Can you believe that?
当然了	I certainly can.
对 真出乎意料	Yeah. Out of the blue.
真出乎意料	Out of the blue.
你们的人生很充实	That's quite a full life.
对 遇到朱莉娅之前 我从未出过远门	Yeah, you know, before Julia, I never traveled.
我甚至从未离开过纽约	I never even left New York.
从未离开过医院	Never left the hospital.
每周七天 从早到晚 从不休假	Seven days a week, dusk till dawn. No vacations.
伊森 我想我有发现了	Ethan, I think I found something.
我平步青云 50岁可以当上外科主任	I was on the fast track to be Chief of Surgery at 50.
55岁 心脏病突发	Heart attack at 55.
她说服我抛弃一切	And she convinced me to let it all go.
去最需要帮助的地方伸出援助之手	Help where it's needed most.
所以从此以后 我们一直四处奔波	So we've been on the go ever since,
我从未感到如此满足	and I've never been more fulfilled.
我真替你感到高兴	I'm happy for you.
谢谢	Thank you.
我们应该走了	Well, we should get going.
我们要收拾行李	We have a lot of packing to do.
不 我来吧 你们俩应该叙叙旧	Oh, no, I'll handle that. You two should catch up.
不 我不打扰你们了	Oh, no, I should get out of your hair.
开什么玩笑你应该留在这里	Are you kidding? You should stick around.
你白跑了一趟 我很遗憾	I'm just sorry you came all this way for nothing.
这样吧 我们打包	Tell you what, we'll pack,
然后开车送你回特图克	and why don't we give you a ride back to Turtuk,
你们俩可以在车里叙旧怎么样	you two can catch up in the car? Yeah?
你真好心	You're very kind.
就这么说定了 回头见	Settled. See you soon.
真高兴见到你	It was good to see you.
我很抱歉 朱莉娅 真的很抱歉	I am so sorry, Julia. I'm so sorry.
把两架直升机都开走	Take both helicopters.
其他人都不能离开	No one else leaves.
小心点	Careful, careful, careful.
已经做好发射准备了	It's armed.
但倒计时尚未开始	But the countdown hasn't started yet.
网络信号很强 这表示另一台设备	The network signal's strong, which means the other device
和引爆器都在附近	is close by and the detonator.
约半公里处 在那个方向	About half a K in that direction.
他们还在这里	They're still here.
卢瑟 你继续想办法拆除炸弹	Luther, you keep working on it.
你们两个跟我来	You two, come with me.
好啊 我能搞定	Oh, sure. I got this.
别担心老伙计卢瑟	Don't worry about old Luther.
（正在扫描）
沃克	Walker.
（已连接）
（准备发射）
该死	Damn.
伊森 倒计时开始了	Ethan, the countdown has started!
我们有15分钟	We have 15 minutes.
引爆器在沃克手上	Walker has the detonator.
快 	Come on, come on!
我们必须让这些人撤离	We have to evacuate these people.
没时间了	There's no time.
整座河谷会在15分后化为灰烬	This whole valley's gonna be incinerated in 15 minutes.
太晚了 	It's too late!
不	No.
我会去拿引爆器	I'm gonna get the detonator.
-什么怎么拿 -我会想办法	-What? How? -I'll figure it out.
找到连恩 找到另一枚炸弹 	Find Lane! Find the other bomb!
-他到底在干什么 -我觉得不看为妙	-What the hell is he doing? -I find it best not to look.
怎么样了 卢瑟	How we doing, Luther?
到处都是绊线 我一个人应付不过来	Tripwires everywhere. I don't have enough hands.
快点搞定	Just make it happen.
伊森在哪	Where's Ethan?
他去拿引爆器了	He's gone after the detonator.
等等 引爆器在哪	Wait, where's the detonator?
卢瑟	Luther.
朱莉娅 你不应该来这里	Julia. You shouldn't be here.
老天	Oh, my God.
真的是炸弹吗	Is that what I think it is?
卢瑟 让她走开 	Luther, get her out of there!
她能去哪里	Where is she gonna go?
我可以做些什么	What can I do?
工具箱里有一把红色手柄钳子	In the kit, the pliers with the red grip.
-你疯了 -管好你自己的事 班吉	-Are you insane? -Mind your business, Benji.
这就是我的事 	This is my business!
班吉 你收到了吗	Benji, do you copy?
伊森 伊森 你在哪	Ethan! Ethan, where are you?
我在直升机里 正在追沃克	I'm in a helicopter going after Walker.
等等	Hold on.
你怎么会进去直升机里	How did you get in the helicopter?
什么你会开直升机	What, you can fly a helicopter?
你说直升机吗	Did you say helicopter?
你在直升机里干什么	What the hell are you doing in a helicopter?
就嘿你们找到另一枚炸弹了吗	Just... Hey, hey... Did you find the other bomb?
我们还在找 但除非我们拿到引爆器	We're still looking, but finding the bomb
否则找到炸弹根本不重要	is not gonna matter unless we have the detonator.
我知道 我会拿到引爆器的 	I know. I know. I'll get it. I'll get it!
如果他在另一架直升机里	If he's in another helicopter,
-你怎么去拿引爆器 -我会想办法	-how are you gonna get it? -I'll figure it out.
你们去找炸弹 我会拿到引爆器	You find the bomb, I'll get the detonator.
我不会让你们失望	I won't let you down.
-做好准备 -听着 伊森 	-Be ready. -Look, Ethan. Ethan!
伊森 请回答 	Ethan, come in!
班吉卢瑟	Benji? Benji? Luther?
有人吗	Anybody?
我能办到	I can do this. I can do this.
这里有什么东西	What do we got here?
有空速	We've got airspeed.
空速	Airspeed.
好 动力 这是动力	Okay, power. This is power.
有效载荷 我如何卸掉这个有效载荷	Payload. How do I get rid of this payload?
动力	Power.
电线退皮钳	Wire strippers.
我是医生 不是电工	I'm a doctor, not an electrician.
抱歉 有绿色手柄那玩意	Sorry, the thing with the green grip.
-拿到了 -我左手里的电线	-Got it. -The wire in my left hand.
-黑色的 -我的左手	-The black one? -My left hand.
-那是你的左手 -抱歉 另外一根电线	-That's your left hand. -Sorry, the other wire.
红色的	The red one?
是的 我右手里的红色电线	Yes, the red one in my right hand.
核对一下	Just checking.
我喜欢她	Oh, I like her.
稳住 好吗	Hold this for me, will you?
老天爷 	Holy shit!
可恶 	Damn it!
飞高一点 	Get up there!
没错	That's right,
混蛋	prick.
该死 	Oh, shit!
王八蛋	Son of a bitch.
好	All right.
太过了	Whoa, whoa, too much. Too much.
该死 	Oh, shit!
往上拉升	Pull up. Pull up.
接近地面 往上拉升	Terrain. Terrain. Pull up.
-往上拉升 -我正在努力 	-Pull up. -I'm trying, I'm trying!
接近地面	Terrain. Terrain.
班吉 我什么都找不到	Benji, I'm not finding anything.
我觉得我们找错地方了	I think we're looking in the wrong place.
到处都有信号	Signatures everywhere.
这是藏炸弹的绝佳地方	This is the perfect place to hide it.
我就是这个意思 我了解连恩 如果我们在这里找	That's the point. I know Lane. If we're looking here,
这是因为他希望我们这样做	it's because he wants us to.
我去村子那里	I'm heading to the village.
等等我 好吗	Just wait for me, all right?
艾尔莎 我有发现了	Ilsa, I think I've found something.
剪断这里这根电线	Cut this wire right here.
朝逆时针方向慢慢旋转那个螺丝钉	Turn that screw counterclockwise, very slowly.
好的	Got it.
那么	So...
他还好吗	How is he?
你知道的 伊森还是老样子	Oh, you know. Same old Ethan.
老天 	Jesus!
该死 	Oh, shit!
不要	No, no, no, no, no, no.
-班吉 我看见连恩了 -什么在哪里	-Benji, I see Lane. -What? Where?
他在村子边缘的一栋房子里	He's in a house at the edge of the village.
好 等等我 好吗	All right, just wait for me, okay?
艾尔莎 等等我 	Ilsa, wait for me!
不	No.
核炸弹	Nuclear bomb.
（X光辐射）
可恶 	Damn it!
班吉 我找到另外一枚炸弹了	Benji, I found the other bomb.
艾尔莎 你在哪	Ilsa, where are you?
我在一栋屋子里	I'm in a house...
嘿 你到底在干什么	Hey! What the hell are you doing?
你疯了 	You're out of your mind!
我不知道下面有什么东西	I don't know what's down there.
往上拉升 	Pull up, pull up!
这个疯狂的王八蛋想撞我们 	This crazy son of a bitch is trying to ram us!
快 	Go!
可恶 	Shit!
班吉 请回答	Benji, come in.
我们马上就要搞定保险丝了	We're almost at the fuse.
我们需要找到另一枚炸弹	We need to find that other bomb now.
你刚刚说另一枚炸弹	Did you just say "other bomb"?
-班吉 收到了吗 -我正在想办法 	-Benji, do you read me? -I'm working on it!
艾尔莎 你在哪	Ilsa, where are you?
你没法阻止此事	You can't stop it.
明白吗他无能为力	Do you understand? There's nothing he can do.
定时器跑完之后	When the clock runs out,
伊森亨特会失去他关爱的	Ethan Hunt will lose everything
所有东西	and everyone
和所有人	he ever cared about.
艾尔莎 	Ilsa!
班吉 	Benji!
艾尔莎 你在哪	Ilsa, where are you?
你可不想看到这一幕	You don't want to see this.
班吉 	Benji!
-艾尔莎  -班吉 	-Ilsa! -Benji!
班吉 班吉 别过来 	Benji! Benji, stop!
班吉 	Benji!
（引擎机油 温度95-97度）
不 不要 	Oh, no, no, no!
（引擎机油 温度155-165度）
稳住	Stay with me. Stay with me.
不 成功就在眼前 不能失败	No, no. Not when I'm this close.
成功就在眼前 不能失败 快 	Not when I'm this close. Come on, come on!
谢谢	Thank you.
把他绑起来	Tie him up.
你为何就是死不了	Why won't you just die?
你已经尽力了	There's nothing else you can do.
去陪你老公吧	Go be with your husband.
卢瑟	Luther...
快去	Go.
班吉 你在哪	Benji, where are you?
好 卢瑟 我们进来了 告诉我们该怎么办	Okay, Luther, we're inside. Tell us what to do.
你应该会看到 连接到主板上的红色电线	You should see the red wire attached to the motherboard.
看到了	Yeah.
你需要同时剪断那一根	You need to cut that and the green wire
和旁边的绿色电线	next to it simultaneously.
好 就位	Okay, ready?
预备	Set?
剪	Cut.
我说过了 没法阻止	I told you. It can't be stopped.
你们无能为力	There's nothing you can do.
班吉 听着 朝逆时针方向旋转那个螺丝钉	Benji, listen. Turn the screw counterclockwise.
好	Yep.
拿开那个主板 你会看到	Remove that panel and you'll see
保险丝的电源和接地电线	the power and ground wires for the fuse.
看到了	Got it.
到那个时候 剪断绿色电线	When the time comes, cut the green wire.
现在不要剪	Do not cut it yet.
好 我们收到了	Okay. We copy.
伊森 如果你能听见 我们要准备剪电线了	Ethan, if you can hear me, we're ready to make the cut.
伊森 请回答	Ethan, come in.
班吉 我们如何知道 他能否拿到按钮	Benji, how do we know if he's got the key?
他会拿到的	He'll get it.
-对 但我们如何知道 -他会搞定 	-Yeah, but how do we know? -He'll get it done!
没时间了 我们只能希望他会拿到	We're out of time. We just have to hope he has it.
-好 我们准备好了 -还剩两秒时剪断电线	-Okay, we're ready. -At two seconds we cut.
等等 为何是两秒为何不是一秒	Wait, wait, wait! Why two? Why not one?
你想距离最终时间这么近才剪	You want to cut it that close?
我们玩不起这一秒钟 	It's a second we'll never get back.
我们能决定吗	Can we make a decision on this?
好 我们还剩一秒钟时剪	All right, all right! We'll do it on one.
还剩一秒钟时剪	Cutting on one?
对 一秒 好 准备	Yes, one. All right, stand by.
三	Three...
-二 -一	-Two... -One.
动手 	Now!
好了	Okay.
好样的	My man.
伊森	Ethan?
你能听见我吗	Can you hear me?
不 不要	No. Don't, don't, don't.
不要动	Don't try to move.
别动 你伤得很厉害	Don't move. You're pretty banged up.
你可真幸运	You're a lucky man.
你坠机后得以生还 真是奇迹 索恩医生	It's a miracle that crash didn't kill you, Dr. Thorne.
如果你的朋友没在一小时后找到你	If your friend didn't find you an hour later,
你会死于冻伤	you would've died of exposure.
-我的朋友 -是的	-My friends? -Yeah.
你才刚离开 她就来了	She got here not long after you left.
还带来了很多印度士兵	Right in front of half the Indian Army.
能让我们单独谈谈吗	Can you give us a few minutes, please?
回头见 医生	See you later, Doc.
朱莉娅	Julia...
对不起	I'm sorry.
根本用不着道歉	There's no reason to be sorry.
不是的	No.
对于发生的一切	I'm sorry
我都很抱歉 我	for everything. I...
看着我	Look at me.
看看我的人生	Look at my life.
我热爱自己的事业 如果我没遇到你	I love what I do, and I never would have
就不会找到这一切	found this if I hadn't met you.
发生的一切	And everything that happened,
让我了解真实的自己 让我明白	it taught me who I am. It showed me
自己的能力 而且我	what I am capable of, and I...
我会活下去	I am a survivor.
但这里发生的一切	But what happened here,
-是我的 -平安无事	-it was my... -Nothing happened.
因为你守候着我	Because you were here.
知道你永远都会与我相守 我便能每夜安眠	And I sleep soundly at night knowing you always will be.
你幸福吗	You're happy?
非常幸福	Very.
我身处自己的归属地	I'm exactly where I should be.
你也一样	And so are you.
根据你的要求	Per your request,
我会把所罗门连恩交给军情六处	I'm handing Solomon Lane back to MI6.
当然是通过中间人	Through a broker, of course.
这是日前安排的一部分	Part of our ongoing arrangement.
巴黎事件之后	After what happened in Paris,
我们更倾向于保持低调	we prefer to keep a low profile.
你的朋友无需 再跟英国秘密情报局打交道了	And that closes your friend's account with British Intelligence.
肋骨 小心我的肋骨	The ribs. Watch the ribs.
我现在明白了汉利为何信任你	I understand now why Hunley believed in you.
世界需要不可能任务小组	The world needs the IMF.
我们需要像你这样的人	We need people like you
你在乎一个人的性命	who care about the one life
也在乎无数人的性命	as much as they care about the millions.
这样一来	That way
我就永远无需担忧	I never have to.
你没事吧	You okay?
你从未像现在这么帅	You've never looked better.
别这样 拜托	Don't. Please.
我们有多险	How close were we?
跟往常一样	The usual.
跟往常一样	The usual?
请别逗我笑	Please don't make me laugh.